<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Informational | CodeAffectionado]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/categories/informational/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-15T04:11:41-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jeff.downing@latchd.com]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey? Whats With This Wordpress Site?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2014/10/16/hey-whats-with-this-wordpress-site/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-16T14:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2014/10/16/hey-whats-with-this-wordpress-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just in case you noticed, there is a Wordpress site out there with the same name as this site. It&rsquo;s still me though. No one is plagiarizing or copying the content off this site&hellip;yet. As a matter of fact, the Wordpress site was an experiment I was conducting to see what the writing experience was like for not only me but possibly collaborators. Unfortunately, it wasn&rsquo;t a very good experience.</p>

<p>To make matters worse, the search engine integration on the other site isn&rsquo;t very keen either. This site, for instance, frequently shows up in the top ten for specific tutorial searches while a Wordpress site with the exact same content doesn&rsquo;t. The majority of people hitting this site are coming from searches so that&rsquo;s not going to cut it.</p>

<p>What does this all mean? Well, in a nutshell, <em>I am going to start writing more tutorials</em> and I needed to settle into a set of tools that I will be doing them in. Before I got too busy, I thought that I would examine the other options. Overall, though, this site is much better prepared to do the job.</p>

<p>By the way, I do read the comments, I&rsquo;m just really awful about replying. I really appreciate all of the positive things you guys have said. If you have any suggestions for topics you would like to see, feel free to comment in the <a href="/labs-and-tutorials/">labs and tutorials</a> section and let me know. I have started outlining some Apache Sling tutorials and have the resources to put together Hadoop tutorials as well, but the sky is the limit. That being said, I need to get writing on of them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
