<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[CodeAffectionado]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-13T18:08:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jeff.downing@latchd.com]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Video: Setup BndTool for JSP Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2015/05/13/new-video-setup-bndtool-for-jsp-development/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-13T17:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2015/05/13/new-video-setup-bndtool-for-jsp-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I worked on a video tutorial on how to setup BndTools with Pax-Web so you can develop JSP applications on it.
I originally found out how to get this accomplished by looking at the imports that Karaf uses when you turn the
features on for it. Translating them to felix wasn&rsquo;t hard but it was time consuming and tedious. In the end you only
need a <a href="https://app.box.com/s/xwvcb9ai5v6ht43tqnnsn9ih706c6b2q">handful of bundles</a> to make it work. I&rsquo;ve zipped them all up and put them on Box.net to make them easier to get started with. Here&rsquo;s the video, enjoy!</p>

<iframe width="625" height="385" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_q7_8yGJ1nM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>It took some trial and error, but after I made it work once, I captured the launch descriptor in a gist which you can see as well:</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/PlasmaTrout/7dd5646a258a664ce8bd.js"></script>


<p>The video link to youtube is on the <a href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/labs-and-tutorials/osgi">labs and tutorials</a> page. I will work on the written tutorial and should have it out in a few days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Set Up for 2015 (Videos and More)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2015/05/13/setting-up-for-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-13T09:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2015/05/13/setting-up-for-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know it&rsquo;s been quiet for a while since the last update, and that&rsquo;s going to change. It just took a while to setup for the new additions
to the site. It took longer than I expected to purchase the software and equipment needed to take this to the next level.</p>

<p>So whats in the works, well, for starters video tutorials. There will be more of those for sure. My first few attempts went into the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCXUMchScrOIZYUa9_6wmFTg">Programmer Vs World youtube channel</a>, but I think I may move them to a dedicated codeaffectionado channel soon.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s an example (I made a <a href="http://localhost:4000/labs-and-tutorials/osgi/">special area</a> in the OSGi tutorial page for these):</p>

<iframe width="625" height="385" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KqhpgiFNQso" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<br/><br/>


<p>Also, myself and a few friends have started getting ready to start a podcast.
We&rsquo;ve done some sample takes and think we&rsquo;ve got a format that can be fun and educational all at the same time. We did some test episodes but we should have the real show cranking up in late June. I&rsquo;ll post the link on here when it starts.</p>

<p>Lastly the site has needed a makeover for quite a while. I&rsquo;ve been running with the stock theme for far too long. Thanks to <a href="http://annekjohnson.com/">Anne Johnson</a> for the theme.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s the next tutorial? Well I received a ton of questions about how to build JSP applications for Felix/BndTools, so I thought we would start there. I have the materials complete, I just need a play to put a zip file of all of the BndTools items you will need first. I also recieved some questions on logging as well and we will tackle that too.</p>

<p>Thanks everyone for being patient the last few months and game on!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey? Whats With This Wordpress Site?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2014/10/16/hey-whats-with-this-wordpress-site/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-16T14:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2014/10/16/hey-whats-with-this-wordpress-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just in case you noticed, there is a Wordpress site out there with the same name as this site. It&rsquo;s still me though. No one is plagiarizing or copying the content off this site&hellip;yet. As a matter of fact, the Wordpress site was an experiment I was conducting to see what the writing experience was like for not only me but possibly collaborators. Unfortunately, it wasn&rsquo;t a very good experience.</p>

<p>To make matters worse, the search engine integration on the other site isn&rsquo;t very keen either. This site, for instance, frequently shows up in the top ten for specific tutorial searches while a Wordpress site with the exact same content doesn&rsquo;t. The majority of people hitting this site are coming from searches so that&rsquo;s not going to cut it.</p>

<p>What does this all mean? Well, in a nutshell, <em>I am going to start writing more tutorials</em> and I needed to settle into a set of tools that I will be doing them in. Before I got too busy, I thought that I would examine the other options. Overall, though, this site is much better prepared to do the job.</p>

<p>By the way, I do read the comments, I&rsquo;m just really awful about replying. I really appreciate all of the positive things you guys have said. If you have any suggestions for topics you would like to see, feel free to comment in the <a href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/labs-and-tutorials/">labs and tutorials</a> section and let me know. I have started outlining some Apache Sling tutorials and have the resources to put together Hadoop tutorials as well, but the sky is the limit. That being said, I need to get writing on of them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New OSGi Tutorial on Bndtools Posted]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2014/10/16/new-osgi-tutorial-posted/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-16T14:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2014/10/16/new-osgi-tutorial-posted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a <a href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/labs-and-tutorials/osgi/apache-felix-scr-annotations">previous osgi tutorial</a> we built a project and tested it utilizing maven. While maven is easy for making simple bundles, it becomes difficult to manage when projects
have many bundles or when projects separate their API and Implementations frequently.</p>

<p>A product called Bndtools streamlines the building of OSGi components and provides a significant number of  tools that help in this arena. In this <a href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/labs-and-tutorials/osgi/apache-felix-maven-to-bndtools">new Bndtools tutorial</a> the original simple greeter service is going to be rebuilt from scratch as a Bndtools project.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/labs-and-tutorials/osgi/">OSGi Tutorial Page</a> has been updated with this tutorial as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Most Important JavaScript Videos You Might Watch This Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2013/09/03/labs-and-tutorials-slash-apache-jackrabbit-slash-importing-xml/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-03T10:54:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2013/09/03/labs-and-tutorials-slash-apache-jackrabbit-slash-importing-xml</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love to watch programming related presentations online, it&rsquo;s sad, but I love it. I typically put these on during my hour commute to and from work and just listen. I did however, run across a presentation from a google conference a few years ago that made me go home and actually watch the presentation. It was Douglas Crockford&rsquo;s &ldquo;JavaScript: The Good Parts&rdquo; presentation. The reason I started over was I didn&rsquo;t get very far into listening when I realized I had a problem.</p>

<p>Early into &ldquo;The Good Parts&rdquo; Doug said something to the extent of &ldquo;JavaScript is a language that people jump in and think they know, but don&rsquo;t&rdquo;. Only a few minutes later into the presentation after some examples, I had an epiphany. I was one of those people. I had just jumped into the language and treated it like Java. It&rsquo;s an utter miracle that my stuff every worked. I decided to start over and take the language and patterns very, very seriously.</p>

<p>Here is a compiled playlist of the important sections of his talks starting from the very origins of JavaScript all the way to advanced usages.</p>

<iframe width="640" height="315" src="http://www.codeaffectionado.com//www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLla7Y38jCBmN_N0BgfyKCy9zJrf3HeWYv" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Take the time to watch this whole playlist. I promise you it will make you better in the long run. If at the very least at code reviews.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newest OSGi Additions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2013/08/19/newest-osgi-tutorial-additions/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-19T14:26:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2013/08/19/newest-osgi-tutorial-additions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/labs-and-tutorials/osgi/">OSGi Tutorial Page</a> has been updated with a few new labs. Coming shortly we will finally have up our blueprint services lab, and we do have a quick Sling final lab that will exploit our basic bundle and add some HTTP capabilities.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Jackrabbit - Starting From Scratch Tutorial Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2013/08/17/apache-jackrabbit-starting-out/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-17T12:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.codeaffectionado.com/blog/2013/08/17/apache-jackrabbit-starting-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our newest Apache Jackrabbit tutorial has been put up on out <a href="http://www.codeaffectionado.com/labs-and-tutorials/apache-jackrabbit/">Apache Jackrabbit Labs Page</a>. We expect quote a few more will start making there appearances soon now that the same code has been written for in class exercises.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
